Guide to the Doris Tobias Papers MSS.265
Fales Library and Special Collections
Doris Tobias Papers
1970-2009
1970-1979
Fales Library and Special Collections
Tobias, Doris
Feigin, David S.
MSS.265
2 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 flat box
Doris Tobias (d. 2009) was a food writer based in New York City. She worked as a food and wine columnist and editor for Women's Wear Daily and Wine & Spirits Magazine. Tobias published several cook books and reviewed numerous restaurants during her career. This collection documents her professional career as a female writer involved in the food industry in New York City during the late 20th century. Materials include recipes, menus, print publications, clippings, food and wine event packets, business cards, financial and apartment contract records, writings, and a toy truck commemorating George Duboeuf's annual Beaujolais Nouveau.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by David S. Feigin in 2009. The accession number associated with this gift is 2009.265.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in the order in which they were recieved from the donor.
Biographical / Historical
Doris Tobias (d. 2009) was a food writer based in New York City. She worked as a food and wine columnist and editor for Women's Wear Daily and Wine & Spirits Magazine. Tobias published several cook books and reviewed numerous NYC restaurants during her career. In June 2008, she was interviewed about her 750 square foot East Village apartment for a New York Times article entitled, "LIVING IN A NUTSHELL; Living Large In Little Apple."
Scope and Contents
This collection documents Tobias' professional career as a female writer involved in the food industry in New York City during the late 20th century. Materials include recipes, menus, print publications, clippings, food and wine event packets, business cards, financial and apartment contract records, writings, and a toy truck commemorating George Duboeuf's annual Beaujolais Nouveau.
Cooking & dining; Food habits -- New York (State) -- New York; Food writers.; Food writing.; Restaurants -- New York (State) -- New York; Women in the food industry.; Feigin, David S.; Tobias, Doris
- Magazines, 1977-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Clippings, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Chips, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Recipes, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letter, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sandwich, 1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Clippings, 1985-2006 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Wine and Health, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Gourmet Gall/March of Dimes, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Recipes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Doris Tobias editorial of Golden Lemon, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Wine Cellars unused material, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Burgundy, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Book reviews by Doris Tobias, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Fifth, Sixth, and Ninth Annual California Vinters Barrel Tasting Dinner, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
- Clippings, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Golden Lemon, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Rose Champagne, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- 2 Beckman Place - contract copy, 1970-2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Clippings, 1974-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Doris Tobias's proposed books, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Clippings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Invitation, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Magazines, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- The Great East Coast Seafood Book, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Menus and press releases, 1975-1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Financial records, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- At Table and related articles, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- At Table articles, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- Press releases, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Writings, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Clippings, 1972-1990 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
- Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Menus, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Pamphlets, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Georges Duboeuf commemorative Beaujolais Nouveau toy truck, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Business cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Menus and press releases, undated (Box Shared Fales 011, Folder 1)